In this lesson, we've investigated two new types of layers for deep networks.
在这节课 我们研究了两种新的深度网络层级类型
We began with convolutional layers which detect regional patterns in an image.
我们先介绍了卷积层 它可以检测图片中的区域性规律
Max pooling layers appear after
最大池化层出现在卷积层之后
convolutional layers to reduce the dimensionality of our arrays.
可以降低数组的维数
These arrays along with
这些数组和更加熟悉的完全连接层
the familiar fully connected layers are often the only layers that you'll find in a CNN.
经常是你在 CNN 中唯一会遇到的层级
In this video, we'll discuss how to arrange these layers to design a CNN architecture.
在此视频中 我们将讨论如何排列这些层级 并设计 CNN 架构
We'll focus on CNNs for image classification.
我们将侧重于图片分类 CNN
In this case, our CNN must accept an image array as input.
在这种情况下 CNN 必须将图片数组作为输入
If we're going to work with messy real world images,
如果我们要处理混乱的现实图片
there's a complication that we haven't yet discussed.
那么将遇到我们尚未讨论的一个难点
If I go online and collect thousands or millions of images,
如果我上网收集数千张或数百万张图片
well it's pretty much guaranteed that they'll all be different sizes.
那么很有可能这些图片的大小各不相同
Similar to MLPs, the CNNs we'll discuss will require a fixed size input.
和 MLP 相似 我们要讨论的 CNN 需要固定大小的输入
Thus, we'll have to pick an image size and resize all of
因此 我们需要选择一个图片大小
our images to that same size before doing anything else.
并将所有图片处理成这一大小 然后才能执行任何其他操作
It's very common to resize each image to a square with
我们经常会重新调整图片的大小 变成正方形
the spatial dimensions equal to a power of two
并使空间维度等于 2 的幂次方
or else a number that's divisible by a large power of two.
或者可以被 2 的幂次方整除的数
In this video and the next,
在此视频及后续视频中
we'll work with a dataset composed of images that have all been resized to 32 by 32.
我们要处理的数据集包含的图片均已重新调整大小 变成 32 x 32
Recall that any image is interpreted by the computer as a three dimensional array.
计算机会将任何图片解读为三维数组
Color images had some height and width and pixels along with red,
彩色图片具有宽高像素
green and blue channels corresponding to a depth of three.
并沿着红色 绿色和蓝色通道 对应深度 3
Grayscale images, while technically two dimensional,
灰度图片虽然本质上是二维的
can also be thought of as having their own width and height with a depth of one.
但是也可以看做具有自己的宽和高 而深度是 1
For both of these cases with color or grayscale images,
对于彩色或灰度图片
the input array will always be much taller and wider than it is deep.
输入数组的宽和高始终会大于深度
Our CNN architecture will be designed with the goal of taking
我们的 CNN 架构的设计目标是获取该输入
that array and gradually making it much deeper than it is tall or wide.
然后逐渐使其深度大于宽和高
Convolutional layers will be used to make the array deeper as it passes through
卷积层将用于使穿过卷积层的数组更深
the network and max pooling layers will be used to decrease the spatial dimensions.
最大池化层将用于减小空间维度
We'll get into the details of why we want to do this a little later in the video.
稍后我们会在本视频中详细讲解为何这么做
But to see how this works,
要了解背后的工作原理
consider following the input layer with a sequence of convolutional layers.
看看下面的输入层 后面跟着一系列的卷积层
Recall from the video on convolutional layers that
记得在卷积层视频中我们提到
this stack will discover hierarchies of spatial patterns in the image.
这些堆叠起来的层将发现图片中的空间规律层级
Each of the convolutional layers requires us to specify a number of hyperparameters.
每个卷积层都需要我们指定超参数数量
For instance, the filters are often square and range from
例如 过滤器经常是正方形
the size of two by two at the smallest to five by five at the largest.
大小范围从 2x2 到 5x5
The stride is generally set to one which you might recall is the default in keras.
stride 通常设为 1 在 keras 中 1 是默认值
As for padding, it's believed that you will
对于填充 如果将其设为 'same'
get better results if you set your padding to 'same.'
我们认为你将获得更好的结果
This is not the default in keras.
在 keras 中这不是默认值
But this combination of setting the stride equal to one and the padding equal to same
将 stride 设为 1 并将填充设为 'same'
has the effect that the convolutional layer has
将使卷积层的宽和高
the width and height that is the same as the previous layer.
与上一层级的相同
As for the number of filters,
对于过滤器数量
recall that this parameter controls the depth of
这个参数控制的是卷积层的深度
our convolutional layers since the layer has one activation map for each filter.
因为层级针对每个过滤器都有一个激活映射
Often, we will have the number of filters slowly increase in the sequence.
经常我们会让过滤器数量逐渐递增
So the first convolutional layer might have 16 filters.
因此第一个卷积层可能具有 16 个过滤器
The second will have 32.
第二层将具有 32 个
The third 64 and so on.
第三层将具有 64 个 以此类推
Of course, for the first convolutional layer,
当然 对于第一个卷积层
we'll have to add the additional parameter of the input shape.
我们还要添加一个参数“input_shape”
In this toy example,
在这个小例子中
assume our dataset is composed of 32 by 32 color images.
假设我们的数据集由 32x32 的彩色图片组成
And we'll use the 'relu' activation function in all of our convolutional layers.
我们将在所有卷积层中使用 relu 激活函数
If we follow this process,
如果按照这一流程操作
we have a method for gradually increasing
这会让数组的深度逐渐增大
the depth of our array without modifying the height and width.
但是不会修改宽度和高度
The input, just like all the layers in this sequence,
输入层和该序列中的所有层级一样
has a height and width of 32,
宽和高为 32
but the depth increases from the input layers depth of three to 16 to 32 to 64.
但是深度从输入层的 3 增大为 16 再增大为 64
Recall that. Yes, we wanted to increase
是的 我们希望增大深度
the depth but we also wanted to decrease the height and width.
但是我们还希望减小高度和宽度
This is where max pooling layers will come in.
这时候最大池化层就派上用场了
They generally follow every one or two convolutional layers in the sequence.
它们通常紧跟在序列中的一个或两个卷积层后面
The most common setting,
最常见的设置是
we'll use filters of size two with a stride of two.
使用大小为 2 的过滤器
This has the effect of making the spatial dimensions
这样可以使空间维度
half of what they were from the previous layer.
变成上一层级的一半
In this way, the combination of convolutional and max pooling layers
这样 通过组合使用卷积层和最大池化层
accomplishes our goal of attaining an array that is
我们就能够获得很深
quite deep with very small spatial dimensions.
且空间维度很小的数组
Let's double check this by entering the code
我们通过在 keras 中输入代码
in keras and seeing how the dimensions change.
看看维度是如何变化的 再次检查下
As promised, the convolutional layers expand the depth of
和预期的一样 卷积层将数组的深度
the arrays from three to 16 to 32 and finally, 64.
从 3 变成了 16 再变成 32 最终变成 64
The max pooling layers decrease the spatial dimensions from
最大池化层将空间维度从 32 减小为 16
32 to 16 to eight and finally, four.
再减小为 8 最终变成 4
This sequence of layers discovers the spatial patterns contained in the image.
这种层级序列发现了图片中包含的空间规律
It gradually takes the spatial data and converts the array to a representation that
它逐渐获取空间数据 并将数组转换为
instead encodes the content of the image
包含图片内容的表示
where all of the spatial information is eventually lost.
所有空间信息最终会丢失
In the original image,
在原始图片中
it's quite relevant which pixel is next to what other pixel.
很容易知道各个像素与其他哪些像素相邻
When you look at how the image has been transformed at the end of this long sequence,
查看在长长的序列之后图片最终是如何转换的
it's no longer important what entry in the array is next to what other entry.
就会发现数组中的条目与哪个项目相邻不重要了
Instead, the array can answer such questions as: are there wheels in the image?
相反 数组可以回答以下问题：图片中有轮子吗？
Are there eyes in the image?
有眼睛吗？
What about furry legs or tails?
有毛茸茸的腿或尾巴吗？
Once we get to a representation where there's
一旦我们获得的表示
no more spatial information left to discover in the image,
不再具有图片中的空间信息
we can flatten the array to a vector and feed it to
我们就可以扁平化该数组
one or more fully connected layers to determine what object is contained in the image.
并将其提供给一个或多个全连接层 判断图片中包含什么对象
For instance, if wheels were found in the last max pooling layer,
例如 如果在最后一个最大池化层中发现轮子
this fully connected layer will transform that information
那么该全连接层会转换该信息
to predict that a car is present in the image with higher probability.
并预测图片中有汽车的概率更高
If there were eyes,
如果有眼睛
furry legs and a tail,
毛茸茸的腿和尾巴
the output layer would take that information and deduce
那么输出层会获取该信息
that a dog is likely present in the image.
并推断图片中可能包含狗狗
But of course, to emphasize all of
当然 模型中的这些理解信息
this understanding in the model is not pre-specified by us.
并不是我们提前指定的
It is learned by the model during training and through back propagation.
而是模型在训练过程中通过反向传播了解的
This architecture that we're specifying here just gives the model a structure that will
我们指定的这个结构只是向模型提供了一个
allow it to train better so that it has
使其能更好地训练的结构
the potential to classify objects more accurately.
从而能够更准确地分类对象
Let's enter this architecture in keras.
我们将此结构输入到 keras 中
Here, I've added only three lines of code.
我在这里仅添加了三行代码
First, I flatten the final max pooling layer to a vector.
首先 将最后一个最大池化层扁平化为向量
Then, two dense layers are added.
然后添加两个密集层
The last layer has a soft max activation function so that it returns probabilities.
最后一个层级具有 softmax 激活函数 以便返回概率
In this case, I've given the final dense layer 10
这里 我将最终密集层的节点设为 10 个
nodes since our dataset will have 10 different object classes.
因为我们的数据集将具有 10 个不同的对象类别
It's also common to give
经常还会向隐藏完全连接层
hidden fully connected layers and CNN architectures a relu activation function.
和 CNN 架构提供 relu 激活函数
And so I've done that here.
我在这里也添加了
We'll work more with this architecture in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中进一步处理该架构
The ideas that I presented here should just be used to get you started.
我在本视频中介绍的理论只是帮你起步而已
To arrive at your own models,
要自己设计模型
you'll have to take a hands on approach with trying
你需要亲自尝试各种架构
out many architectures and different hyperparameters.
和不同的超参数
Deep learning is a hands on field,
深度学习是一种需要实践操作的领域
so don't be afraid to get your hands dirty and don't be afraid to break the rules.
所以不要怕麻烦 不去实践 并且不要担心违背了规则
Try out as many things as you can,
尽量去尝试不同的事物
ask questions and experiment to answer
提出问题并通过实验来回答你的问题
your questions rather than just thinking deep thoughts.
而不是仅仅思考
If this is your first time training CNNs,
如果这是你第一次训练 CNN
it will take some time to develop your intuition.
那么需要一段时间才能有直观的感觉
But keep trying. Don't get too discouraged if your early ideas fail.
但是要继续尝试 如果一开始的想法失败了 也不要气馁